XUAN LIU

xuanliu1005@outlook.com

♀ Sydney, Australia **८** (+61) 466343166

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am currently a research postgraduate student at The University of Sydney majoring in Data Science. I received my first master's degree in Industrial Economic from Wuhan University of Technology and bachelor's degree in Mathematics from Hebei Normal University. My research interests are in the area of **Computer Vision**. Particularly, I have experience on Computer Vision and Deep Learning.

EDUCATION

University of Sydney

Sydney, Australia

Master of Data Science (Research Pathway)

Jul. 2023 - present

GPA (first semester): 4.00/4.00

Wuhan University of Technology

 $\it Course:$ Machine Learning and Data Mining (88/100), Computational Statistical Methods (86/100)

Wuhan, China

Master of Economics — Industrial Economics (Academic Master)

Sep. 2020 - June. 2023

GPA: 3.78/4.00

Course: Intermediate Microeconomics (85/100), Intermediate Macroeconomics (85/100), Intermediate Econometrics (84/100)

Hebei Normal University

Shijiazhuang, China

Bachelor of Mathematics

Sep. 2016 - Jun. 2020

GPA: 3.32/4.00

Course: Probability and Statistics (94/100), Modern Algebra (100/100), Point Set Topology (94/100), Advanced Algebra (84/100)

PUBLICATIONS & PRE-PRINT

- Xuan Liu, F. M. (2023) Research on the impact of national targeted investment on industrialization: Based on "156 projects" (Master's thesis). Wuhan University of Technology.
- Xuan Liu. Policy suggestions for optimizing the New Nationwide System–From the perspective of "156 Projects". 4th International Symposium on Frontiers of Economics and Management Science (FEMS 2023), Macao, China, 2023[C].

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Wireless signal based Human Pose Estimation

Feb. 2024 - Present

Dec. 2023 - Feb. 2024

Supervisor: Dong Yuan

Supervisor: Zhiyong Wang

The University of Sydney

Research Pathway Project

- Reproduce the paper model: Xie C, Zhang D, Wu Z, et al. RPM 2.0: RF-based Pose Machines for Multi-Person 3D Pose Estimation[J]. IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology, 2023.
- Create a new multi-scale contrastive learning to deal with pose estimation with rare pose and strong reflection interference.
- At this stage I am building models and conducting experiments.

Reality and Virtuality: Generating Wireless Communication Data

The University of Sydney

Summer Research Project

- Generate and collect Wi-Fi Channel State Information (CSI) from virtual environment and real world.
- Set up a hardware environment to collect CSI data, for subsequent use in Wi-Fi based pose estimation.

The Long Term Impact of "156 Projects"

Wuhan University of Technology

Feb. 2022 - May. 2023 Supervisor: Yanyan Tang

• Fill the gaps in the quantitative assessment of the long-term impact of the "156 Projects" in the two dimensions of time "vertical" and regional "horizontal".

• Explore the theoretical mechanism of the long-term impact of the "156 Projects", identify four "channel variables" and explain their impact, and analyze the long-term impact of project investment on the four "channel variables" respectively.

INTERN EXPERIENCE

Product Manager, JD.com, Platform Operation and Marketing Center

Dec. 2022 - April. 2023

- Participate in the design and review process of the Short Product Details Page, contributing insights and expertise to ensure an effective and user-friendly design;
- Leveraged analytical skills to extract pertinent data for thorough analysis, enabling the estimation of Return on Investment (ROI) potential for new product initiatives;
- Fostered effective communication and collaboration between business, design, and Research & Development (R&D) teams, ensuring alignment of objectives and streamlined project execution;

Business Support, JD.com, Explore Academy

Dec. 2021 - Sep. 2022

- Successfully participate in managing the end-to-end process of major international conferences, including the World Artificial Intelligence Conference (WAIC), ensuring seamless execution and exceeding participant expectations;
- Facilitated contract negotiations and compliance, liaising with stakeholders to ensure accurate representation of terms and effective resolution of any discrepancies;
- Produced engaging and informative content, including PowerPoint presentations, scripts, interviews, and speeches, effectively communicating complex concepts to diverse audiences;

ACTIVITIES

USU VTeam Volunteer, The University of Sydney	Aug. 2023 - Present
Postgraduate Assistant, Wuhan University of Technology	Sep. 2020 - Dec. 2021

AWARDS & SCHOLARSHIPS

• Summer Scholarship, The University of Sydney	Dec. 2023 - Feb. 2024
• The second prize of excellent student's scholarship, Wuhan University of Technology	2020-2023
• The second prize of excellent student's scholarship, Hebei Normal University	2017-2020